<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Licton Springs Community Council - Licton Springs Community Council</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/feeds/licton-springs-community-council.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://lictonsprings.org/</id><updated>2020-10-21T18:30:00-07:00</updated><subtitle>Building Community Since 1990</subtitle><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes Oct 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-oct-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-10-21T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-10-21:/council-meeting-minutes-oct-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes Oct 21, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Ellen Beck, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Dianne Trani, Tracy Cramer, Osbaldo Hernandez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie started the meeting at …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes Oct 21, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Ellen Beck, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Dianne Trani, Tracy Cramer, Osbaldo Hernandez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie started the meeting at 6:35 and welcomed everyone.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of Sept 21, 2020 were approved as circulated.  Treasurer’s Reports was approved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1, Group discussed letter from ALUV sent to Geoffrey Wendtland January of this year to Office of Planning and Community Development. Ryan DiRaimo had emailed it to LSCC October 7 to keep us informed. It appears many planning projects are on hold due to disruptions caused by current COVID 19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LSCC and UNEA/Clear Sky relations and purchase of tee-shirts to thank the UNEA youth.  melanie has already received orders and M/S/A to spend up to $500 for the shirts.  Liz attended the Sept 30 UNEA virtual meeting and noted once the pandemic is over, there might be volunteer opportunities with UNEA, for example, tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie invited visitors to address us. Tracy Cramer Clean City Division City of Seattle discussed community cleanup efforts, such as one for November, ate TBD. She also introduced us to Jenny Frankl, Sr Planning &amp;amp; Development Specialist Public Place Littering &amp;amp; Recycling Program, Clean City Division. Tracy and the group discussed clean up in the parks and neighborhood, particularly given recent City decisions on homeless encampmens.  Liz noted the Parks Dept would be doing a cleanup in Licton Springs Park Oct 22. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dianne Trani attended and noted her boss, Brian Robinson, a local property owner with various rental properties and a commitment to affordable housing and helping on neighborhood issues, would love to hear from LSCC on ways he could be of assistance.  Lindsey requested some help contacting renters who might be interested in joining us to add a diverse voice to the Council and help with outreach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osbaldo Hernandez from DON has replaced the retired Thomas Whittemore and introduced himself. He noted that community conversations has been initiated, with the next scheduled for Nov 18, probably on the topic of public safety. http://www.seattle.gov/neighborhoods/outreach-and-engagement/community-conversations &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several LSCC members attended the recent virtual town hall  held by Debra Juarez and reported on the budget presentation, looking on our screens at the Powerpoint slides (Ben Noble, Dean Allsopp) indicating some real shortfalls in revenue to the City that are necessitating putting many activities on hold, such as moving ahead for now with the feasibility study for an Aurora-Licton Community Center. Melanie also reported on the group discussing public safety (Indian Health Board and Community Police Commission, Esther Lucero and Ryan Gilbert) and Jason Johnson for City Human Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group considered a request from Board member Amanda Crosley for support for North Seattle College Co-Op Preschool (see Oct 19 email from Amanda). The Board authorized a $150 donation and Janice will get in touch with Amanda and request preference for the donation to go to local area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice is still following up with Restricted Parking issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We affirmed that we cannot hold our holiday event this year due to the pandemic and city restrictions on parks since we usually hold it in Mineral Springs Park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we plan to have an event to celebrate Jan Brucker’s years of service once we are able to hold events in person, for now, Kathleen and Ellen will deliver the recognition award to Jan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie reported on a Greenways meeting re Healthy Streets and Healthy Blocks initiatives and indicated there is still lack of clarity on all processes to designate streets or blocks as such. Healthy Streets are ones that had already been designated as Greenways but the blocks process not clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes by Kathleen Braden, secretary, LSCC
Next meeting Nov 18&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes Sept 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-sept-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-09-17T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-09-17:/council-meeting-minutes-sept-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL
approved Minutes Sept. 17, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Ellen Beck, and
Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup, Fadi Saloum, Mike Cuadra, Bekah …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL
approved Minutes Sept. 17, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Ellen Beck, and
Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup, Fadi Saloum, Mike Cuadra, Bekah Manikowski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:35 and welcomed everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of July 15, 2020 were approved as circulated. Treasurer’s Reports for July and through Sept.
12, 2020 were approved. Ellen also noted she filed our required yearly report with Wa State Sec. of
State’s office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion of purchasing tee-shirts for One Sky youth as a donation: The cost for eleven tee shirts
would be approx.. $262. This organization has had to move from Eagle Staff School to north Seattle
College and several Board members are in touch with leaders of the organization, including Sarah
Sense-Wilson. Council decided to reach out to Sarah and ascertain what program needs are and if the tee
shirts would be a welcome donation. The group weighted the symbolic importance of the shirts due to
their design using the indigenous language vs uncertainty about the needs of One Sky. It was also
M/S/A to invite Sarah to a future Council meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz Kearns provided a great set of updates to various neighborhood issues (attached below) and thank
you also to Lee Bruch and Susan Ward for the information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz also noted that the expansion of the North Precinct Police Station out- buildings and parking area is
now completed. The group then discussed the situation for people living without shelters in Licton
Springs park. Liz felt that there was a response to the letter the Council sent to get a cleanup initiated by
parks Dept employees. She noted there is still water there in the drinking fountain but the bathrooms are
locked and portable toilets provided. Several of the people there have received referrals to other housing
options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neighbor Bekah Manikowski, attending the meeting, has a social work background and shared her
thoughts on the situation in the park. She is concerned about the health of the people there given the
unhealthy air quality indices at the present time due to forest fires in Northwest
.
Janice had initiated a conversation with Karina Wallace of the NGO “Facing Homelessness” and
Kathleen followed up with a phone conversation with Karina. She sent these links to the Council:
- To sign up/review orientation and Facing Homelessness opportunities :
https://facinghomelessness.volunteerhub.com/
-  The BLOCK Project : https://www.the-block-project.org/
- Facing Homelessness website : https://www.facinghomelessness.org/
- Facing Homelessness Facebook page : https://www.facebook.com/HomelessInSeattle/
Karina also offered to visit a future meeting or even to go to the park and talk with the people camping
there. She noted the organization does a sock drive, takes donations, and often sponsors cleanups. It
also is sponsoring the construction of DADUs (detached accessory dwelling units) and has an
orientation once a month. The organization especially likes to show images of unsheltered people and
tell their stories on their website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed the changes to the Community Police teams and the moving of Officer David
Gordon out of the role he has held for many years. Kathleen will draft a thank you email to officer
Gordon that also notes that LSCC is following this issue with cc to North precinct captain, new police
chief, and Council Rep. Juarez. She will circulate a draft for approval. The vote was 5 yes and one
abstain to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie noted with regret that our usual Halloween event in Licton Springs Park will not be possible
this year due to the continuing COVID-19 pandemic and everyone agreed this was a sad, but wise,
decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsey gave a recap of the Music-in-the-Neighborhood event this summer that was a success. But we
also have some ideas on how to modify and improve it for next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Cuadra expressed thanks for the Council’s letter regarding zoning and the Halcyon Mobile Home
park in North Seattle. Bekah Manikowski discussed the importance of a get-out-the-vote effort at the
local level and she will write up a short paragraph about it and send to Janice so we can post it to our
list-serv and other sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice concluded the meeting and thanked everyone. Next meeting will be by zoom Oct. 21.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ADDENDUM (Thank you, Liz Kearns, for collecting this information)
STAY HEALTHY STREETS---Transportation/Seattle gov.
Here's the official city webpage on them:  http://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-
programs/programs/stay-healthy-streets
From Lee Bruch:
It is an initiative in response to Covid that has been launched in many cities nationwide to give more
space for people out moving and exercising while maintaining 6 feet of social distance (where we have
sidewalks, most sidewalks are only 5 to 6 feet wide, not allowing people to pass while maintaining
social distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locally, it was launched by Mayor Durkan and SDOT fairly quickly.  They specifically chose to launch it
on Greenways since those were already in place as slow traffic streets prioritizing pedestrians and
bikes over cars.  Here's an article when they were
launched:  https://sdotblog.seattle.gov/2020/04/16/announcing-stay-healthy-streets/ .  Here's another
article talking more in-depth about pros and cons:  https://westseattleblog.com/2020/05/stay-healthy-
streets-explained-discussed-seattle-pedestrian-advisory-board/
Since that first announcement the network has gradually been expanded in response to public usage
and popularity.  The StayHealthy Streets program was for an indefinite length of time, roughly
estimated originally to last through Sept, or more recently, into October, depending on usage. I'm not
aware of any final date having been determined, but I &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; the current intent may be to keep
them until towards the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mayor and SDOT announced mid-summer that roughly 20 miles of them will be permanent. Which
20 miles is still being decided I believe, depending on results of various public surveys and traffic
counts SDOT has undertaken, results of some collision studies, city money issues, etc.
See  https://www.myballard.com/2020/05/08/seattle-to-make-20-miles-of-stay-healthy-streets-
permanent/
They are not closed to all traffic. They are meant to allow local traffic to serve the particular block, but
where pedestrians and bikes have the right-of-way (sort of like cul-de-sacs in suburban
neighborhoods).
Northgate Pedestrian &amp;amp; Bicycle Bridge---Transportation/Seattle.gov
Here is the link to Bridge information, and you can sign up on their mailing list for monthly or every
other month updates.
http://www.seattle.gov/transportation/projects-and-programs/programs/bridges-stairs-and-other-
structures/bridges/northgate-pedestrian-and-bicycle-bridge
NG Ped/Bike Bridge cont.
What we’ve heard through design.
Based on community input throughout the project, we know there’s interest in:
Minimizing environmental impacts of the bridge by making sure, for example, that the project doesn’t
disturb wildlife during construction and ensuring the bridge’s drainage system (for stormwater) is
designed to enhance wetlands on the west end
Ensuring safety and security of all bridge travelers Wayfinding and traffic control The experience of
people biking and using other wheeled devices (e.g., scooters, wheelchairs, strollers, rollerblades,
suitcases, etc.)
Connecting the bridge to other infrastructure, including neighborhood bike routes
Separating or managing modes of traffic on the bridge
Other topics of interest included the project’s cost, the bridge’s durability, and maintaining vegetation.
Thank you Susan Ward for sending this link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIRE STATION #31
There is a land use sign at 1319 N Northgate Way saying it will be demolished.
An article in The Seattle Times 5.6.20 calls this building ‘The Cancer House’ and states the project
budget cost is $43M for design and construction of new Fire House.
The land use sign at Epic Life Church states their east parking lot will become a temporary Fire Station&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;31 with tents and 13 parking spaces.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Seattle Times article (mentioned above) also states the City of Seattle will pay Epic Life Church
$10,000.00 a month for 5 years to lease this land.
Again, The Seattle Times article states the new site for FS#31 is 11302 Meridian Ave N
I drove by this address and there is no indication that anything is planned for this site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes July 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-july-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-15T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-15T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-07-15:/council-meeting-minutes-july-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approved Minutes July 15, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Ellen Beck, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:35 and welcomed everyone.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approved Minutes July 15, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Ellen Beck, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:35 and welcomed everyone.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M/S/A to have Kathleen draft a letter to Councilwoman Juarez expressing our concern about unavailability of public restrooms at Licton Springs Park due to campers’ items and presence blocking access. Kathleen will send a draft to LSCC members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M/S/A June 19, 2020 minutes as circulated.  There is no Treasurer’s Report for this period although Ellen did note a donation received. She will update us later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed producing tee-shirts via a print-on-demand company, Zazzle, recommended by Janice (https://www.zazzle.com/).  The group discussed design ideas and M/S/A to allocate funds to pay a designer recommended by Melanie. Janice okayed the idea with Tom Speer of UNEA in conversation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group continued planning on August 19 event to make use of City’s invitation to use some of Arts in the Park event money since the full event could not occur due to the current virus.  Thank you to Janice and Lindsey for doing much of the planning re outreach to secure musicians and indigenous artists.  John at the UPS Store at Oak Tree offered to give us a good rate on yard signs and flyers to publicize the event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LSCC received a request from John Lombard of D5 for support for a letter re zoning of the Halcyon Mobile Home Park to keep it available as a mobile home property.  The letter is still being constructed and M/S/A to authorize Janice and melanie to decide if LSCC can lend support for the letter once it is completed, since we do not meet in August. Melanie in particular would like to get more information from John and some of the model actions, such as Bothell’s, he referred to in portions of it drafted so far. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting is in September. (16th) but it was decided to delay further Board member selection processes until 2021 because of anticipated ongoing restrictions due to the COVID-19 pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes June 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-june-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-19T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-19T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-06-19:/council-meeting-minutes-june-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes June 19, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Ellen Beck, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Susan Ward, Janice Holkup, Mike Cuadra, Mehul Shah, Dianne Trani, Sharon …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes June 19, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, Ellen Beck, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Susan Ward, Janice Holkup, Mike Cuadra, Mehul Shah, Dianne Trani, Sharon Bruce&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:35 and welcomed everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our invitation, Susan ward of ReVisioning Northgate, attended and updated LSCC on activities around the Northgate area and actions taken by RN. She noted it was formed at grassroots level to advocate for green spaces and livable spaces and includes representatives from various on-profits as well as residents and businesses. The group discussed transportation issues, the underpass beneath I-5 at Northgate, METRO and its projects, including bus staging areas, parking impacts with impending light rail station, affordable housing, the tree code. The current pandemic has limited in-person meetings for the organization but it has been active in submitting commentary and letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of May 20, 2020 were approved as distributed. The treasurer’s report through was approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group then turned to having an activity that is community-oriented. Janice noted we were informed that while our arts in the Park project was on hold due to pandemic, the City did allocate $1600 to LSCC for any culture-related activity in the neighborhood, particularly promoting diversity and justice and combatting bias. Janice shared the email and offered by email and at the meeting a set of ideas on how to use the funds. (attachment) Janice will check with our partners at Clear Sky, Dianne train offered to look into musicians, and Melanie suggested we do tee-shirts. Lindsey and Janice will do some organizing on a possible event in August. The date of August 19 seemed most likely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was agreed we would touch base on whether to have a Board retreat in the fall, similar to the one we had Sept. of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group then discussed the issue of recruiting a more diverse Board membership. Kathleen noted data from 2010 census that indicated Licton Springs is one of the more ethnically and racially diverse neighborhoods north of the ship canal. (attachment) The group discussed the current climate for change, given local and national issues. Mehul weighed in about the need to do outreach to people who are not homeowners, perhaps leaving flyers near apartment buildings. Janice will provide the information about the local renters she met who were doing volunteer clean-up. Lindsey and Mehul offered to do a draft of a recruiting tool poster. Janice offered to write up a statement that could be posted on our web site and Facebook page. Kathleen, who is also a block watch captain, will contact North precinct officer David Gordo to see if there are any special instructions for people neighboring the precinct building and send it along to the Board if she receives any information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes by Kathleen Braden, secretary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting July 15 by Zoom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATTACHMENTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email from Janice June 12, 2020 to the Board:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are receiving $1,600 to do something for the neighborhood to uplift residents by providing creative, artistic, and/or cultural content. The requirements seem very loose. Given these funds were was originally ear-marked to celebrate the sacred indigenous status of Licton Springs I’d love to put some of the funds toward that AND we can do anything. Below is the start of a brainstorming list. Any other ideas? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hire local artists to paint mail boxes in the neighborhood.  \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Develop, record, and host a podcast series, in partnership Clear    Sky, to celebrate the LS designation \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy colored chalk for the neighborhood to create their own sidewalk     murals. Take pictures and post on our Facebook and Instagram pages  and the blog \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring local artists to make chalk murals around the neighborhood \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring musicians to perform and stroll through the neighborhood on  different nights throughout the summer - bagpipes, saxophone,   trumpet, accordion, banjo, guitar \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin forwarded message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From: &lt;/strong&gt;"Crooks, Jenny" &amp;lt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Jenny.Crooks@seattle.gov&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject: Updated Arts in Parks Process and Funding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: &lt;/strong&gt;June 11, 2020 at 11:46:44 PM PDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To: &lt;/strong&gt;"&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;janicelichtenwaldt@me.com&lt;/span&gt;" &amp;lt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;janicelichtenwaldt@me.com&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cc: &lt;/strong&gt;PKS_artsinparks &amp;lt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;artsinparks@seattle.gov&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Arts in Parks Partner,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your patience during these difficult and challenging times for our communities.  The work that many of you continue to do to support your community through all of this has been truly inspiring.  While we are no longer able to fund your originally proposed project in full, we are looking forward to working with you to support the work you are doing that benefits our community.  Seattle needs arts and culture now more than ever. We need you and the role you play in our sector’s ecosystem and in the civic life of our City as a whole. Even if the way you carry out your work has shifted, the value you provide cannot be underestimated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWARD AMOUNT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attached invoice is for $1,600 to support a public benefit in lieu of your original project and funding amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HERE’S ALL YOU NEED TO DO:      &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respond &lt;/strong&gt;to this email to confirm that you have received it and with a brief description of the action or project that will take the place of your originally funded event and provides artistic or cultural public benefit (please see the backside of the attached invoice-report form for suggestions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should be an action or project that is in the spirit of and supports the goals of the Arts in Parks program, of supporting under resourced communities within Seattle and supports the efforts of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://seattletogether.org/"&gt;Seattle Together&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;which include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uplift residents by providing creative, artistic, and cultural    content&lt;/strong&gt; (digital and analog) to residents, especially     vulnerable populations, by resourcing artists, organizers and other     cultural partners.  \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevate, support, and uplift mutual aid efforts&lt;/strong&gt; for     community resilience, efficacy and recovery driven by a dynamic     understanding of racial equity, neighborhood-level and cultural     community relationships, and digital technology access.   \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Combatting bias/hate speech/harassment/violence&lt;/strong&gt; amidst  Covid-19, with an awareness of how this could have impacts on   surveillance and policing practices disproportionately impacting    BIPOC communities. \&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small-scale projects are fine and if it aligns with work that you were planning on doing to benefit your community, even better. It can be something done via an email, online, virtually, through social media, or any other method of distribution that aligns with public health guidance for physical distancing. We’re not looking for you to spend significant time making something happen. We are hoping the prompts will inspire your imagination, be forward thinking and accessible.  At this time, these funds should not be planned to go towards a postponed in-person park event.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ask that whatever action or project you do, to please include the tag #SeattleTogether and the City of Seattle logo found here: &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/arts/about-us/download-our-logo"&gt;http://www.seattle.gov/arts/about-us/download-our-logo#tabs-5&lt;/a&gt; or provide written credit. (For example: “This project was supported by Arts in Parks, a partnership with Seattle Parks and Recreation and the Seattle Office of Arts &amp;amp; Culture.”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete&lt;/strong&gt; an action that provides artistic or cultural public benefit.  Please email a link and/or promotional item/information about your project at least a week prior to it taking place so that we can help share it out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submit your invoice and report&lt;/strong&gt;. Once your project is complete and available to the public, complete the attached invoice form and email it to &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;jenny.crooks@seattle.gov&lt;/span&gt; along with your brief narrative report. Please include a link of where to access your project or attach with your invoice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;           We do need your signature on the form. If you don’t have a printer/scanner, you can save the invoice form as a pdf and use the attached instructions to sign it electronically.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may invoice anytime in 2020 through November 30, 2020 but we highly recommend doing so before &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;August 31, 2020&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once received, the City will send you payment. On average it can take 4 weeks for you to receive payment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep us posted if either your primary contact or authorized signer changes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASSISTANCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to answer any questions you have. If you need additional support, feel free to contact Jenny at &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Jenny.Crooks@seattle.gov&lt;/span&gt;.  If you would like to set-up a phone call to discuss possible projects, please include some windows of availability M-F 10am-4pm in your email.  If for some reason you feel like you are not able to complete an action or project associated with this funding, please reach out to discuss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With much appreciation, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny Crooks (she/her)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arts Program Manager | Seattle Office of Arts &amp;amp; Culture &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal line: 206.684.7084 | Office Line: 206.684.7171&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office Address: 303 S. Jackson Street, Top Floor, Seattle, WA 98104&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mailing Address: Jenny Crooks - Seattle Office of Arts and Culture, PO Box 94748, Seattle, WA, 98124-4748&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/arts"&gt;seattle.gov/arts&lt;/a&gt;  | &lt;em&gt;Making Art Work&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.facebook.com/SeattleArts"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SeattleArts"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/seaofficeofarts/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href="https://confirmsubscription.com/h/y/D4F100F4F392F6FE"&gt;Subscribe to ARTS Enews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ARTS at King Street Station&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;303 S. Jackson Street, Top Floor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle, WA 98104&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free Admission; Open Tuesday – Saturday, 10 a.m. – 6 p.m.; First Thursdays, 10 a.m. – 8 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the Office of Arts &amp;amp; Culture’s opportunities, programs, grants, public art, youth arts, cultural space and Langston Hughes Performing Arts Institute please visit us at &lt;a href="http://www.seattle.gov/arts"&gt;seattle.gov/arts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes May 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-may-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-20T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-05-20:/council-meeting-minutes-may-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes May 20, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup, Mike Cuadra, Lindsey’s cats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes May 20, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Melanie Davies, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup, Mike Cuadra, Lindsey’s cats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:35. She welcomed everyone. Mike Cuadra introduced himself as a former Board member. There was a discussion of zoning and urban village boundaries. Melanie will reach out to ALUV to see if there is any news on zoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a discussion of progress at Northgate and the Board decided to invite Susan Ward to participate in our next meeting, June 17, by zoom, if she is available to update us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of April 15, 2020 were approved as distributed. The treasurer’s report through May 20, 2020 was approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay Healthy Street Program- many signs are up to close streets off in our neighborhood for vehicle traffic, as is being done throughout the city, due to the pandemic and need to maintain social distancing while people are out exercising. Janice attempted to reach Debra Juarez about the question of neighborhood input if the closures re made permanent, but she did not hear back despite also copying in her staff. Liz talked about meeting a parking enforcement officer while she and Ellen were walking but that the officer had no information about the program. Melanie suggested talking to ALUV and Greenlake CC. We looked at the West Seattle blog website and noted that Seattle Pedestrian Advisory Board and Greenways have been instrumental in the effort. The first public discussion did not occur until four weeks after the first closures were announced. Melanie and Janice will follow up. Lindsey suggested reaching out to Dan Strauss. Kathleen can contact Lee Bruch. Melanie will forward notes from Licton-Haller Greenways meeting (attached).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 7 Durkan virtual town hall- Janice and Melanie attended. Janice presented our question about budget implications for Licton Springs neighborhood. The bottom line is that funds will be scarce to non-existent for projects due to huge decrease in sales tax revenue during the pandemic and business closures. Melanie provided the links sent out from the town hall and they are attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz asked what sort of services we could offer to the community and noted she received a nice thank you letter from Washington Food Fund for our contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Seattle College- Janice is our rep. and she noted that Chemane Crawford is the new interim president. We discussed the location of future residence halls on their campus but noted that due to the pandemic, it was less likely the halls would be constructed in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arts-in-the-Park- although we received a greenlight for next phase of our project recognizing Licton Springs park as sacred space to Native Americans, the funding is cancelled for now from the City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen noted that the recruitment of people to an Advisory Board for the LSCC is put on hold until the fall due to the slowdown of activities with the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie reported on Seattle Arts Commission decision on temporary placements of art pieces that will be at either 92&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; or 100&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; streets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen noted that Mary Amberg was leaving the police dept to take a job in the private sector and she had sent an email thanking Mary for her service to our neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Board agreed that the June and July meetings should be held via Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes by Kathleen Braden, secretary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting June 17 by Zoom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATTACHMENTS&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes April 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-april-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-15T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-04-15:/council-meeting-minutes-april-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes April 15, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Amanda Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup, Tracy Cramer, Thomas Whittemore, Noah An, Dan …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes April 15, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Amanda Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees: Janice Holkup, Tracy Cramer, Thomas Whittemore, Noah An, Dan Strauss, Mehul Shah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of March 25, 2020 were approved as distributed. The treasurer’s report 3/26 through 4/14/2020 was approved.  Ellen said the next report would reflect full amount received re brevity donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City Council Representative from District 6, Dan Strauss, and his staff person, Noah An, attended.  The Council members thanked them for their time. Dan gave an overview of activities at his office during this time of COVID-19 contraction. He is holding meetings with constituents over the phone and continuing work on housing and transit issues.  He noted that Licton Springs borders both Districts 5 and 6 so he is available for inquiries from Licton Springs residents. Amanda asked him about the City Council work during the COVID-19 period and Dan explained that work continues, though at  a low level and there are lots of suggestions coming from the state government.  He noted the constraints on rents now and the strain on small businesses.  Melanie asked about his perspective on the community center plans for Licton Springs-Aurora and he noted he and Juarez are working cooperatively and he is following her lead on the issue. He noted that childcare is one of his priorities.  Kathleen asked about cooperative work among Strauss, Juarez, and Pedersen for North Seattle. Strauss reminded us that as a City Council rep. he is called upon to work on behalf of the whole city, not just District 6. He believes work on a new police station for the North Precinct should be coordinated- he recently did a “ride along” with North precinct staff. He concluded his visit by thanking Thomas Whittemore for delaying his retirement due to the current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jordan Haselnus of Seattle Neighborhood Group was not able to attend but sent in a proposal for a cooperative effort to do a street cleanup in the Licton Springs- Aurora area or at Mineral Springs park.  Tracy Cramer noted that last year, the group did an amazing job. She will contact Jordan about her idea.  The group agreed that litter cleanup is important, but prefer to wait until the governor’s stay at home order is lifted in May so as not to send the wrong signal, especially since the City has suspended its own clean up campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice and Tracy will write up a short piece about litter cleanup work for the Love Licton blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice and Kathleen noted that the Bloodmobile has been suspended for now and Bloodworks is booked into May for individual appointments. Kathleen sent out a plea for support of local foodbanks to our listserv, but has not yet gotten any responses. Lindsey noted the Washington Food Fund under the governor’s council and Philanthropy Northwest (&lt;a href="https://philanthropynw.org/wa-food-fund"&gt;https://philanthropynw.org/wa-food-fund&lt;/a&gt;). M/S/A for LSCC to donate $200 each to the Washington Food Fund and to Epic Life Church for their neighborhood food bank.  Kathleen will send Ellen the addresses so she can send paper checks to each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen reported on an effort to get North Precinct Block Watch captains organized for neighborhood self-help. Thomas Whittemore reported on the Seattle Together program by the City- it is a work in progress and will need guidance and approval. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed the ReVisioning Northgate email  from Susan Ward on the rerouting of bus routes around the Northgate area.  Kathleen will forward her email to the Council. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council agreed to discuss in the future the prospect of having a credit card or a debit card for the Council’s bank account.  Ellen will report at the May meeting on the rider for Public Schools on our insurance coverage, due to be renewed in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice provided images of some tee-shirts and other swag souvenirs with the Licton Springs cattail logo that could be manufactured and sold on demand both to raise money and create neighborhood solidarity. The Council will proceed with this although it was noted we need to take care of the tax and potentially, business license, implications.  Melanie is going to check with a friend who does design about the logo.  Janice, melanie, and Lindsey will form a team to see if it is possible to launch this effort by May 2, which is Neighbor Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes by Kathleen Braden, secretary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting May 20 either by Zoom or in Licton Springs Park.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes March 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-march-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-03-25T18:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T18:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-03-25:/council-meeting-minutes-march-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes March 25, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Amanda Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Tim Crosley, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neighbor attendee: Janice Holkup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;approved Minutes March 25, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online meeting by Zoom due to Corona virus restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Amanda Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, Tim Crosley, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neighbor attendee: Janice Holkup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of February 26, 2020 were approved as distributed. The treasurer’s report 02/25/2020          through 03/25/2020was approved.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Communication recommendation approved&lt;/span&gt;: during this time of COVID-19 Stay Home order from Governor Inslee, not make any major changes in manner of sending messages to our list serve, but continue to use free Outlook service.  Help was also offered to the Love Licton blog for material and Amanda and Tim are trying to keep it at very local level.  A lot of information is being pushed out right now by City, King County authorities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsey and her husband, Mehul, are walking each street of Licton Springs neighborhood and will do a write-up and send Amanda.  Mehul is interested in LSCC eventually doing a community survey on loneliness and isolation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was noted that neighborhood restaurants are open for takeout and it is a good way to support business owners locally. Lindsey will follow up with Hector Martinez at Epic Life church who is with the local Buy Nothing group as well and see if something can be written up for the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz noted that the parks are closed so no work parties are now occurring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminder that people should be filling out Census 2020 information.  Field operations have been moved till later due to virus outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice Holkup reminded people of Kathleen’s proposal that was on the table from the Feb 26 meeting.  She has attached it below for consideration at April meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice L. gave an update on Arts in the Park and that she has been in contact with Sarah Sense Wilson of Clear Sky.  The event will be pushed out to late August or Sept. in part to wait for City to do final approval of historic status for the park. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nominations for the Board and vote on approval will be moved to next September due to unusual circumstances of COVID 19 outbreak and to allow more time for recruiting new members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes by Kathleen Braden, secretary.  Next meeting April 15, 2020 by zoom. &lt;a href="https://zoom.us/j/521529297"&gt;https://zoom.us/j/521529297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PROPOSAL FOR ADVISORY BOARD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From: Kathleen Braden, LSCC secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;February 26, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose: (1) advise on issues that are pertinent to the neighborhood, especially those identified by ongoing surveys of the neighborhood; (2) provide advice when requested by the Board; (3) make suggestions on Board members to recruit in future &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing contact to be made over cyberspace so that people are not required to attend meetings but attendance at LSCC meetings is welcomed and encouraged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City Council Representative of District Five or designated staff contact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owner of business located within Licton Springs boundaries or adjacent community council boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;person from neighborhood school either staff or parent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representative from North Seattle College&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;community officer from North precinct or NPAC rep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representative of ALUV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;resident in Licton Springs boundary who is a renter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representative from a social services group in neighborhood such as LIHI or Aurora Commons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;two residents of Licton Springs neighborhood (this might be good place for “emeritus” member who used to serve on the Council?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If approved, what’s next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motion is to modify the by-laws.  According to the by-laws, this would have to be voted on at the general membership meeting, which occurs in April. Results determined by majority vote of members attending (not just directors)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add Article VIIA  Licton Springs Community Council Advisory Board&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The purpose of the LSCCAB shall be to advise on issues pertinent to the Licton Springs neighborhood and assist the LSCC in recruiting Board members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The LSCCAB is not require to have regular meetings, but the chair of LSCCAB may call special meetings under certain circumstances. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication is expected to occur largely electronically among members and to the LSCC Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Term of service will be for two years and renewable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members shall consist of:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-City Council Representative of District Five or designated staff contact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owner of business located within Licton Springs boundaries or adjacent community council boundaries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;person from neighborhood school either staff or parent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representative from North Seattle College&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;community officer from North precinct or NPAC rep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representative of ALUV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;resident in Licton Springs boundary who is a renter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;representative from a social services group in neighborhood such as LIHI or Aurora Commons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;two residents of Licton Springs neighborhood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members shall be nominated by LSCC Board of Directors and approved by majority vote of directors at any regular meeting of the Board&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removal of members shall be decided by majority vote of the LSCC directors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article VIII 4c&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add to duties of the Secretary: The secretary shall be responsible for regular contact management with members of Advisory Board and reports from LSCCAB to LSCC Board of Directors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we vote on the motion in March to be considered in April, then we should share some responsibility for recruiting initial members.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes January 2020</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-january-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2020-01-22:/council-meeting-minutes-january-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(unapproved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unapproved Minutes January 22, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascadia School Library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Amanda Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Ellen Beck, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People introduced themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of Nov. 20, 2019 were approved …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(unapproved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unapproved Minutes January 22, 2020 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascadia School Library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Amanda Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Ellen Beck, Liz Kearns, Lindsey Webb, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People introduced themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes of Nov. 20, 2019 were approved as distributed. The treasurer’s report 11-19-2019 through 1-15-2020 was approved.  Ellen noted that there was an additional deposit made and she would include it on the subsequent treasurer’s report. Amanda discussed her work with Randy Wiger on the proposal for the off-leash dog area at Mineral Springs Park. M/S/A that Licton Springs will contribute the value of Amanda’s work hours on this project for the future development of the proposal.  She estimates it as $100 thus far.   The group also discussed using the funds earmarked for Licton Springs Park, possibly for a summer event, with Liz’s approval because of her work as the forest steward for the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed the designation of Licton Springs Park for historic status, given its significance to the Native American communities of the region.  The process is underway and has almost reached the last stage for approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debora Juarez (referred to in these notes below as DJ) and her staff member, Shayna Daitch (SD), joined us (delayed due to police activity in downtown Seattle due to a shooting incident earlier). DJ discussed her understanding of the history of some issues associated with the Duwamish tribe and their designation. She said the Parks Dept .(Superintendent Jesús Aguirre) had informed her of the designation decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of a survey of Licton Springs area residents was discussed.  DJ had it with her as LSCC had sent the results ahead and distributed a summary on our listserv (attached below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DJ was asked to update the group on plans for a feasibility study of an Aurora-Licton Springs Community Center. She discussed the role of Jesús Aguirre and the Parks Dept. which will work with a community group to start the process.  $150,000 has been designated.  SD will be the point person staff contact.  DJ noted that the 6 year cycle for funding for Parks and Recreation is approaching and the feasibility study should be completed in a year.  She discussed her effort to secure the funding and the fact that the neighborhood is located in a “community center desert” in the City.  The PDOC (Park District Oversight Committee) is key to the process and once the 2020 census data comes in, that should help make the case.  DJ noted that this neighborhood has seen much growth of &lt;em&gt;families&lt;/em&gt; in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DJ then discussed all the activity occurring in District Five and how the Aurora, Northgate, and other neighborhoods are morphing into true family-oriented areas.  She talked about the need for sidewalks, a perennial problem in North Seattle. (note: residents from the Licton Springs neighborhood attended and asked her questions during the meeting so some of these notes are her responses to the questions). Subsequent to the 2019 general election, she has met with Council members Dan Strauss (District 6) and Alex Pedersen (District 4) to coordinate on issues impacting North Seattle and she is encouraged about how the representatives will work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She focused on infrastructure and development around Northgate and emphasized that much of the construction will be down with local union labor.  Newer low income housing will be constructed in the Northgate area and any current resident displaced will be able to move back in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked about plans for the North Precinct Police Station, DJ reviewed what was the impediment to earlier plans to build a new station. Plans are till underway and there will be community hearings at North Seattle College.  Lisa Herboldt is now chair of the committee that will deal with the issue and DJ is hopeful action will happen. DJ noted that the City is still handicapped by the insufficient number of police officers and we need to be attracting many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Webb asked about plans for a grocery store at Northgate and DJ said she is pleased with cooperation from Simon (major property owner) but City officials can only do so much where private property is involved. She has discussed, however, the demographics and character of the neighborhood and her preference for a union-shop grocery store to move into the new development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neighbors from Interlake Avenue asked about attention to development west of I-5, such as the need for a supermarket, and raised concern about the focus not being solely around the Northgate area. The group then discussed with DJ the need for attracting businesses along the Aurora corridor, including small enterprises, and reviewed pushback from Aurora Merchants to past efforts such as the moratorium and other work spearheaded by ALUV.  Again, DJ reiterated that where private property and a state highway (99) is involved, the City has a more limited role.  She discussed her efforts to work with Seattle Public Schools as the owner of the Oak Tree Village property, but that headway has not yet been made for any firm plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice Lichtenwaldt noted the work of ALUV and the new group, “For North” and that she has been attending some ALUV meetings and in contact with Casey Pier and there is hope to have a new phase of cooperation with business owners in the Aurora area. Amanda Crosley asked what LSCC can do to be helpful about encouraging business development, for example, with the west side of the upcoming pedestrian-bicycle bridge across I-5.  DJ noted the complications because of N Seattle College and University of Washington ownership of much of the land where the bridge ends up on the west side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking ceremony for the bridge construction is coming up soon. SD noted that there is a need for letters of support for DJ who is calling for speeding up the Sound Transit plans for the 130&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; St light rail station to make it designed for a 2024 opening (to match Lynnwood link) rather than wait until 2031, which doesn’t make sense. SD will email Kathleen Braden with appropriate contact addresses to pass along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group was very happy to receive the news from DJ that the Home Zones projects are approved for money in the City budget.  In addition, SDOT has allocated $40,000 out of the regular SDOT budget for a Licton Springs Home Zone, a project supported earlier by LSCC, spearheaded by Amanda and Tim Crosley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group thanked Council Rep. Juarez and Shayna Daitch for attending and then proceeded with other business after they had to leave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resident Brigette Arden suggested that the survey done by LSCC be repeated on a regular basis to have a longitudinal record of responses and members of the LSCC Board agreed. The group discussed clean-up issues and problems with the 95&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and Interlake area, especially associated with litter. Tracy Cramer, with Seattle Public Utilities and the person who deals with clean-up, attended and discussed how to report problem areas and the best way to send information to the City so that there can be a good response. She noted in particular the limitations the City or Public Utilities are under legally with respect to RVs and a 25 ft perimeter where crews are constrained about removals of trash. She took the information and said they will try to send out a crew to do cleanup on Stone Ave. N.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda gave a report on the December 21 Mineral Springs holiday celebration and thanked everyone who participated. About fifty people attended despite the rain.  LSCC plans to do this event again in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen noted that we now have an electronic archive of the minutes dating back to the 1990s although there are some missing years from the mid-1990s.  It will be posted on the LSCC web site and can be searched using keywords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice Lichtenwaldt noted the upcoming grants workshop Jan. 25 at Bitter Lake if anyone wanted to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen Braden noted the KIRO radio selection of Liz Kearns for their “Hometown hero” award in December.  Liz said she would be doing a work party for the park with second-graders from Cascadia School. Amanda reported on the Jan 20 tree plating at 85&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and Meridian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several Board members attended the January 5 Open House at North Seattle College on the I-5 Pedestrian-Bicycle Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ellen proposed that LSCC order more copies of the Licton Springs brochure and the item will be on the agenda for the Feb. 26 meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATTACHMENT: 2019 Survey of Licton Springs Residents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survey ran from November 13th, 2019 to January 6th, 2020 and received 69 responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top themes included concerns over RVs in our neighborhood, state of the sidewalks (especially north of 100th), interest in additional retail / commerce. Many neighbors expressed thanks for the efforts of the community council.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top issues for the neighborhood include safety &amp;amp; crime, cleanliness/litter control, need for a community center, and business development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The majority of respondents are long term residents, living in Licton Springs for more than 5 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 29% of respondents had ever attended a LSCC meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook, Nextdoor, LSCC emails and LoveLicton are the main sources of information for the neighborhood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 respondents expressed interest in occasional service, 11 expressed interest in an advisory neighborhood group and 11 expressed interest in committees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Top issues for the neighborhood include safety &amp;amp; crime, cleanliness/litter control, need for a community center, and business development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes November 2019</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-november-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2019-11-16:/council-meeting-minutes-november-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approved Minutes November 20, 2019 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascadia School Hallway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Amanda Crosley, Tim Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Ellen Beck, Liz Kearns, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30. She asked people present to introduce themselves …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approved Minutes November 20, 2019 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascadia School Hallway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Amanda Crosley, Tim Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Ellen Beck, Liz Kearns, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30. She asked people present to introduce themselves. Dianne Trani from jet City Property visited and Lindsey Webb who will soon be joining the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasurer’s Report of Oct 16-Nov 20 2019 and minutes from October 16 2019 were approved with correction of typo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Events and applications&lt;/span&gt;: Amanda had completed the Arts in the Park application for a Dec. 21 event at Mineral Springs Park and LSCC was awarded the grant.  There will be a clothing drive, music, food, card making, and sugar plum elves. Entertainment and a port-a-potty will be provided and Amanda is currently in process of recruiting volunteers.  Kathleen will help Liz who is looking into finding another musician group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz noted the Dec 7 lighting for Licton Springs park and the lights will be up until Jan 11.  Epic Life Church will have a small ceremony to turn on the lights and Liz noted that special care will be taken for the safety of the light hangers.  Liz will send Kathleen an announcement to post and to ask for LED light donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group noted the summer movie program for Mineral Springs Park and the application that was submitted for a Native American celebration in Licton Springs Park in July (thank you Janice!).  We discussed whether we would need a business license from the City of Seattle and if it turns out we need it due to revenue amount, Janice will look into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie reported on Halloween event and had emailed Kathleen the cost and donations summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Musicians                              $100.00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candy                                   $171.25&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cider                                     $49.40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total                                     $320.65&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donations                             $203.77&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz reminded us of the second-Saturday work parties in Licton Springs Park and the group noted the press coverage of the Landmarks Preservation Board action regarding Native American significance of the park (reported in &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Seattle Times&lt;/span&gt; and Crosscut). Liz said there will be 3-4 work parties coming up for Mineral Springs Park and while there have been some rough campers there, tent campers have not been observed.  The disk golf people also plan some work parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Online vote results&lt;/span&gt;- the board voted by email to add the City of Seattle to our insurance coverage and to allocate $500 toward the matching grant portion of the application for the Native American summer celebration grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Other business&lt;/span&gt;- Amanda noted that the Parks Dept felt LSCC did not need a business license and will send Kathleen verification of that for the record.  She reported on our Paypal account to take donations and recommended transferring money to our bank account on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen will send out a reminder to people to fill out our survey.  Debora Juarez plans to attend our Jan. 15 meeting and we agreed we can send her the survey results ahead so she knows that issues are on the minds of Licton Springs residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz asked LSCC members as individuals to send letters of support for an effort by Thornton Creek Alliance to keep funding for Green Seattle Partnership in City budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice reported that Leah Anderson from ALUV was reaching out to local community council leaders for a get-together. Melanie, Liz, and Kathleen reported on a recent ReVisioning Northgate meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen reminded people to send bios and pictures for our web page if they have not yet done so. Janice expressed early-Thanksgiving appreciation to members of the Board who in turn thanked her for serving as president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was Thomas’s last meeting as a member of the Board and he noted he had enjoyed serving and would help as he was able in the future. Thank you for your service, Thomas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice closed the meeting at 8:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes October 2019</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-october-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2019-10-16:/council-meeting-minutes-october-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(unapproved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unapproved Minutes October 16, 2019 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascadia School Library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Amanda Crosley, Tim Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Ellen Beck, Liz Kearns, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30 and all are happy to be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(unapproved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unapproved Minutes October 16, 2019 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cascadia School Library&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Amanda Crosley, Tim Crosley, Janice Lichtenwaldt, Ellen Beck, Liz Kearns, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice started the meeting at 6:30 and all are happy to be able to hold meetings inside the Cascadia School.  She asked people present to introduce themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasurer’s Report of Sept 19-Oct 16 2019 and minutes from June 19 2019 were approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie reported on upcoming Halloween event for Licton Springs Park and noted we could use one more volunteer for the Friends of the Forest positions.  She thanked Ellen for taking on the cider table.  We appreciate how long Liz handled this function for us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robin Amadon and Aisaya Corbray from Low Income Housing Institute (LIHI) made a presentation on plans for a mixed income structure on Aurora Avenue at the Nesbit site where the tiny house village was located until this year.  LIHI envisions a seven-story structure and 118 units (see attachment). If all goes well, LIHI is hoping to have it opened by spring 2022.  Robin discussed funding sources, design, and plan for mixed types.  Parking will  not be provided but LIHI hopes to attract people who use non-automobile forms of traffic.  She also discussed ways to secure the walls until construction can start to discourage tagging.  LIHI would like future help from LSCC in announcing public meetings as the project proceeds.  Kathleen will email Robin and Aisaya the email addresses for the LSCC directors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric Blumhagen, who is a candidate for the Seattle School Board, visited and discussed some of the issues he feels are most important and asked for input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Whittemore of the Seattle Department of Neighborhoods discussed the City’s efforts to ensure a good rate of participation for the upcoming 2020 census.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leah Andersen from ALUV vii\sited and discussed the meeting held recently with Debora Juarez and efforts to find funding for a feasibility study for an Aurora-Licton Springs Community Center.  She noted possible availability of a parcel where Quiring Monuments are currently located on Aurora. There will be an upcoming budget discussion and D. Juarez has proposed funding for the study and Leah would like to see support from the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M/S/A &lt;em&gt;he Licton Springs Community Council supports the efforts of Debora Juarez to secure funding for a feasibility study to create a community center for the Aurora-Licton Springs area. The LSCC will continue to monitor this issue and communicate progress to our neighborhood email list of residents and via other social media platforms&lt;/em&gt;. Kathleen will send to the City Council and to Deputy Mayor Moseley and post to the Licton Springs Facebook page, send to email list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed various assignments for Board members that came out of the Sept Board retreat. Amanda, Janice, and Kathleen will follow up re a survey of residents and also Kathleen will post notes from the retreat unless she hears any objections by email before Oct 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice reported on communications with schools and North Seattle College. The group discussed plans for a residential facility at the college (which may be delayed) and the one year extension of the P-Patch on the college grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megan Hazen gave us addresses for parent groups from Cascadia and Eagle Staff schools and said that development of regular communication would be good between the PTAs and the LSCC: &lt;a href="mailto:communications@Cascadiapta.org"&gt;communications@Cascadiapta.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="mailto:info@eaglestaffptsa.org"&gt;info@eaglestaffptsa.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz noted that Epic Life Church will be doing holiday lights in the Licton Springs park again.  She and Janice attended the Landmarks Preservation Board meeting Oct. 16 and the request for Licton Springs park to have historic status was approved.  It will make the park the only Native American site in the City so designated.    Janice will send a congratulations message to Urban Native Education Alliance people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas presented ideas on signage to solicit people who might be interested in joining the Board and Kathleen discussed the possibility of having an Advisory Board for the Community Council. The group also agreed to set up a “who we are” part of our website to identify Board members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas will be leaving the Board after December and Lindsey Webb was unanimously approved to be appointed to fill in Thomas’s term per Article VII-4 of by-laws. [^1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice closed the meeting at 8:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Retreat Notes September 2019</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-retreat-notes-september-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2019-09-19:/council-retreat-notes-september-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;NOTES FROM SEPT 28, 2019 RETREAT LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 AM – 12 PM at Meridian Center for Health, Seattle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notetaker: Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Board members present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Thomas Stachiw, Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Amanda Culp-Crosley, Timothy Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;NOTES FROM SEPT 28, 2019 RETREAT LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 AM – 12 PM at Meridian Center for Health, Seattle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notetaker: Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Board members present: Janice Lichtenwaldt, Liz Kearns, Thomas Stachiw, Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Amanda Culp-Crosley, Timothy Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members thanked Janice for her organization and the room decorations to get us in a productive mood!  Various members brought in food and beverages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice distributed documents including an agenda and time allocation for each item to keep us on track. She welcomed everyone and explained the plan for the retreat. Board members reviewed accomplishments for 2018-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members were then invited to state what they felt priorities should be for 2019-20 and Melanie Davies noted items on the whiteboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group then reviewed some operational guidelines for how the discussion would proceed.  Janice created a “Parking Lot” space for the whiteboard for items that occur to members but that we would park for subsequent discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group reviewed data on LSCC activities and some population profile data based on 1990 and 2010 Censuses to get an idea of distinctives of Licton Springs neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ellen Beck gave a Treasurer’s report and the group discussed ideas on financial side (more fundraising, more equipment, more events, paying for a newsletter editor and distribution, grants to reflect our diverse community, Arts in the Park, visit-consult with Mark mendez of Lake City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice brought up the manner in which we take donations and payment of dues.  Amanda noted Amazon Smile and Janice and Ellen are going to verify that we are set for that  Kathleen will check on access to Paypal account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice noted her hope that we will create both a fundraising committee and a marketing-outreach committee and that we not miss the chance for some items we might sell such as tee shirts or bumper stickers. She noted such committees do not need to be just Board members but we could recruit members of the community who might be willing to serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda discussed how we might use existing funds we have in our account.  Melanie noted the City’s fundraising workshops for community activists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other issues that were brought up included relations with schools in area, including North Seattle College, parking issue sin neighborhood, historic status of Licton Springs park and surrounding neighborhood, more on fundraising, and business relations, particularly with advent of NORA (North Aurora Business, a brainchild of Epic Life Church). Jan noted the passing of Faye Garneau and she will be sending a message of condolence on behalf of the council, pointing out Faye’s contribution to citizen activism as a business owner in the area.  Jan also underscored her interest that the Council start a system to have recognition of people/organizations who have made a positive impact on Licton Springs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Board members then engaged in a prioritization process and various people agreed to be point people on the priorities as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Janice—School relations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz- Licton Springs historic status (park, neighborhood)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie- representing LSCC to other meetings and organizations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen &amp;amp; Thomas- Recruiting more Board members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda- Events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim- engagement &amp;amp; efficiency for monthly meetings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Board voted to allocate $400 to Melanie to support the upcoming Halloween event.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Retreats"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes February 2019</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-february-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2019-02-20:/council-meeting-minutes-february-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feb 20, 2019 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 110 Meridian Center for Health 10521 Meridian Ave N, Seattle, WA 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;see link for map, directions, and bus connections:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/health/locations/north.aspx"&gt;http://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/health/locations/north.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Thomas Stachiw, Ellen Beck, Melanie …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feb 20, 2019 6:30-8:30 P.M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Room 110 Meridian Center for Health 10521 Meridian Ave N, Seattle, WA 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;see link for map, directions, and bus connections:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/health/locations/north.aspx"&gt;http://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/health/locations/north.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directors present: Thomas Stachiw, Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Amanda Crosley, Tim Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introductions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes Jan. 16 , 2019 were approved as distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Letter from Tim Motzer to Debora Juarez from Lake City Neighborhood Alliance (attached) asking for the Council's endorsement. Directors discussed it and had questions about the fee structure and asked Kathleen to send note to Tim declining but that we hope in the future to have a discussion on MHA and fees with other community groups such as LCNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As FYI, Kathleen provided map of MHA zooning proposals and list of amendments that are up for vote in March by City Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion of Handy Andy business on Aurora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda brought up Your Voice Your Choice request for proposals deadline approaching Feb 22 and the Neighborhood Street Fund program with votes due soon on proposals for Licton Springs and adjacent areas  Kathleen will send out to listserv remainder for people to go online and vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group discussed various techniques used by SDOT and DON that creates competition and even "popularity contests" among competing projects proposed by citizens.  Melanie suggested a letter about District Five being poorer than other districts in terms of sidewalks. Kathleen updated the group on proposal to improve signage in Licton Springs Park and her frustration with DON processes when this should merely be part of regular Parks maintenance schedule. She noted her intention to cease efforts to make a DON large grants proposal and will inform the d-hoc committee brought together in the fall, as well as PNA who had agreed to serve as sponsor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda noted we did not get picked for the Arts in the Park projects and will explore other possibilities.  She will be looking into various grant options like Small Sparks and Neighborhood Matching Funds.  Kathleen suggested that any money LSCC had agreed to set aside from our parks fund for signage in Licton Springs Park might be redirected as matching seed money for the Arts or event projects Amanda is thinking of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie noted that Epic Life Church might do another Celebrate North Seattle event. It might be good to invite someone from the church to our next meeting. She also discussed ALUV efforts to do a zoning change from commercial to neighborhood-commercial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed the Home Zone project, SDOT, data on traffic measurement and Ed Irwin applying for speed bumps for traffic calming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie noted the Aurora pedestrian bridge artwork is now up and the daffodils planted there will soon be blooming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen noted that City Council District Five candidate John Lombard had indicated a desire to be at one of our meetings and the group noted he is welcome to come and listen but we have not had a tradition of inviting candidates in for their campaign promotions.  Kathleen will email him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes by Kathleen Braden, secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting is our general membership meeting March 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/lake_city_letter_2019.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lake City Letter" src="/images/lake_city_letter_2019.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting March 20, 2019 6:30 PM   This is our annual General Membership Meeting according to Article VI of our by-laws.  Kathleen needs to post the notice to our email list no later than March 10 of the meeting. There are annual President's and Treasurer's Reports given at this meeting VI-2) and it is at this meeting when we nominate people for positions. Terms are up in March for: Thomas Stachiw, Kathleen Braden, and Amanda Culp-Crosley (who replaced Rose Whitson)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes September 2018</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-september-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2018-09-19:/council-meeting-minutes-september-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Minutes of Sept 19 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Thomas Stachiw, Tim Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas convened the meeting by having everyone introduce themselves and talk about what issues they …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Minutes of Sept 19 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Melanie Davies, Liz Kearns, Thomas Stachiw, Tim Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas convened the meeting by having everyone introduce themselves and talk about what issues they were interested in putting forth. A neighbor from 105&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; St expressed her concern about crime, drug use, prostitution in neighborhood.  Melanie offered to send her the anti-crime information Mary Amberg had provided at our June meeting. A representative from Seattle Neighborhood Group discussed the community safety survey going out regarding the 8800 block of Nesbit. Kathleen will send out the link to the listserv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 20, 2018 minutes and Treasurer's Report were approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen moved to spend approx. $78 for a banner for the Community Council to be used at neighborhood events. Seconded and approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie discussed upcoming Halloween event in Licton Springs park and the need for Friends of the Forest volunteers.  Melanie would like to also interest Eagle Staff parents and students to help.  melanie requested $400 for cost o musicians, cider, and candy.  MindyLee Irvine also is putting together a map of safe trick or treating houses in the neighborhood.  Seconded and approved to spend the $400 requested.  Melanie will communicate with Emma Medicine Whitecrow of the Licton Springs neighborhood and schools to see if costs can be reduced by coordinating with the schools. Jan expressed a desire to see Native American representative images of animals at the event.  Emma also discussed the work at the schools and the hope to inspire and excite the children about tribal sovereignty of the land at Licton Springs park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Speer of Urban Native Education Alliance made a presentation, explaining as well his role as an elder and his concern for Licton Springs' historic significance. He noted that the Duwamish people have been in the area for 15,000years because tribal traditions date back to the Ice Age.  He stated that there were originally three springs at the park: Sulphur, iron oxide, and magnesium.  As of today, only the iron oxide spring is intact. He expressed dismay about the graffiti, needles, trash, excrement, and prostitution in the park. He also noted the significance of the park to the David Denny family and that David Denny, unlike other Dennys, had been a friend to local Native Americans.  Speer spoke for a group that is advocating for designation of the park as a historic landmark, with accompanying signage to explain the historic significance of the park. LSCC is requested to write a letter supporting the designation, as noted by both Thomas Speer and other visitors present such as Matt Remle, who provided a notebook of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emma called for more money for education directly, rather than, for example, the money spent on the Andrew Morrison murals.  There was a general discussion about designation of historic places in Licton Springs area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathleen asked questions about the impact of a historic designation o the park management of the space and wants to be cautious about potentially negative interaction between City depts. that might inadvertently be harmful to use of the park. The group at the meeting also discussed federal recognition of tribes.  Melanie affirmed Liz's role as forest steward for the park. and Kathleen gave an update on a proposal underway to DON to upgrade the signage in the park (Kathleen, Liz, Emma, Amanda Culp, and Joseph are all on the committee).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;melanie reported on ALUV and the moratorium on development along Aurora.  Home Zone- Greenways is also looking at ways to slow traffic in some areas around Licton Springs.  A recent meeting on the topic had good attendance and there is a survey link on the Love Licton blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan, Ellen, and Amada discussed 501 c 3 status restoration.  Amanda moved spending the $275 for reinstatement application. This was seconded and approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan brought up her dislike of the placement of portables at the new schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting adjourned at 8:35. Minutes submitted by Kathleen Braden, secretary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting Oct 17, 2018&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Informal Notes from July meeting</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/informal-notes-from-july-meeting.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2018-07-18:/informal-notes-from-july-meeting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Informal Notes from July 18 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(there was not a quorum at this meeting to conduct official LSCC business)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Tim Crosley, Joseph Amman, Liz Kearns, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph convened the meeting at 6 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Informal Notes from July 18 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(there was not a quorum at this meeting to conduct official LSCC business)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Tim Crosley, Joseph Amman, Liz Kearns, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph convened the meeting at 6:40 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasurer's Report and minutes of May 16, 2018 will be approved at September meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Susan Ward, Sean Watts, Lee Bruch, and two new members of the community attended and discussed issues of concern, particularly related to public safety in the Licton Springs neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sean, Susan, and Lee discussed sending a docent to the upcoming July 31 field trip for City Council Reps. Gonzalez and Mosqueda to District Five.  Susan prepared some talking points that the group discussed and then made suggestions, thanking Susan. Sean agreed to serve as a docent. The LSCC members present agreed to Sean's service and thanked him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was adjourned at 8:30 PM.  Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting Sept. 19, 2018&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes June 2018</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-june-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2018-06-16:/council-meeting-minutes-june-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Minutes of June 20 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Tim Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas convened the meeting at 6:40 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasurer's Report and minutes of May 16, 2018 were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Minutes of June 20 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Tim Crosley, Jan Brucker, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas convened the meeting at 6:40 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasurer's Report and minutes of May 16, 2018 were approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda Culp presented an initial proposal to establish a dog off-leash area in Mineral Springs Park, following the City of Seattle guidelines for making a proposal (which Amanda and Tim Crosley distributed, along with a map of the park and location of other areas). Melanie suggested giving the Park Meridian residents a heads up. M/S/A that Licton Springs Community Council be a sponsoring organization to move ahead with the proposal to create an off-leash area in Mineral Springs Park per application process with Seattle Dept. of Parks &amp;amp; Recreation and include public outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Mary Amberg&lt;/span&gt;, Seattle Police Department Crime Prevention Coordinator made a presentation on neighborhood safety.  Mary explained her role, the role of David Gordon, community police team coordinator for our area, and the services they can provide. She showed a map explaining the boundaries and outlined the various issues David deals with in the neighborhood.  Visitors from the community asked questions with concerns about safety and police response when 911 Is called.  Mary explained the 911 prioritization system and noted that the police &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; respond but they might not come in person other than a drive-by survey unless a "request contact" phrase is used by caller to actually have an officer come to the door. Mary discussed the Navigation Tea, and outreach, cleanup of homeless camps, the use of the Find It-Fix It application, and the best way to report campers.  She reviewed the statistics for the N3 beat within the North Precinct where Licton Springs is located. She urged people not to leave &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; in cars because of car prowls. The current plan for the North Precinct building was discussed. She noted the LEAD program (Law Enforcement Aided Diversion) is coming to the precinct and officers are in training now. More officer shave been budgeted for patrols around the Aurora Encampment. She provided "Smart 911" cards from King County for people who might want their information to be recorded since there is currently not a way for an exact location to be tracked just from a cell phone. &lt;a href="https://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/it/e-911-program/smart-911.aspx"&gt;https://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/it/e-911-program/smart-911.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary noted that one can call the North Precinct and put in a "request to watch" for neighborhood or house and, provided the officer has time, it will be done on a regular basis.  She noted that King County keeps the sex registry and a map for the Licton Springs neighborhood can be seen online [https://www.kingcounty.gov/depts/sheriff/sex-offender-search.aspx]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Licton Springs Web Page&lt;/span&gt;- Timothy showed us the proposed new web page for the Licton Springs Community Council which includes archived existing page.  He and Amanda had also scanned in old copies of &lt;em&gt;Currents&lt;/em&gt; and added a link, as well as a link to the North Precinct, things to do in the neighborhood, green space, discussion page, community calendar, and many other features.  The Licton Springs Community Council members complimented Tim &amp;amp; Amanda on it. M/S/A to commission Tim to go ahead with it and Kathleen will put him in contact with Lisa Henry to get codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Lee Bruch on Aurora Coalition, D5 plans-&lt;/span&gt; The May 31 forum sponsored by D5 with at-large City Council representatives went well, with about 150 people attending. In July, there will be vehicle-tours of District Five neighborhoods with Mosqueda and González over a two day period, July 27 (Northgate and Lake City) and July 31 (Licton Springs, Haller Lake, Bitter Lake).  Lee called for docents to help with the tour and make presentations at various stops, as well as assistance with handouts. Both ALUV and Licton Springs should participate. Jan suggested Liz for the park and discussed issues related to City Light land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group then discussed concerns about plans for the North Precinct police station (portables, new parking area).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was adjourned at 8:40 PM.  Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next meeting July 18, 2018&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes May 2018</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-may-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2018-05-16:/council-meeting-minutes-may-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Minutes of May 16 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Joseph Amann, Tim Crosley, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas convened the meeting at 6:40 PM. People attending introduced themselves and explained issues …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(approved)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Minutes of May 16 2018&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Directors Present&lt;/span&gt;:  Ellen Beck, Melanie Davies, Thomas Stachiw, Joseph Amann, Tim Crosley, and Kathleen Braden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas convened the meeting at 6:40 PM. People attending introduced themselves and explained issues they were interested in including park safety, cleanliness of neighborhood, school lighting, crime prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasurer's Report: Ellen noted a few items, such as the fact she paid the InMotion web hosting bill and filed the 99n from with the IRS and deposited two membership checks. The Treasurer's Report for April 1-30 2018 was approved as distributed. M/S/A the minutes of April 4, 2018 as distributed by email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lou-Anne Daoust-Filiatrault from Seattle Public Utilities visited and presented information on an SPU pilot Litter Abatement Program.  Licton Springs will be the next neighborhood chosen for the program.  Two workers clean litter from Aurora Avenue and some nearby streets twice per week on Tuesdays and Fridays. Licton Springs was chosen as a result of the number of issues raised by residents to the City. The litter cleaning cannot be done in parks or on private property under this program. SPU also hopes to expand in the future the number of sharps disposal containers available since there are only eight city-wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licton Springs and Mineral Springs Parks- Randy Wiger of City Parks &amp;amp; Recreation is holding two more public meetings, June 5 and July 3 and trying to get more people from disc golf community to attend.  Joseph reported on the recent work party in Licton Springs park. Kathleen noted the cordoning off around the restroom is due to roof and skylight repair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;M/S/A Kathleen will send a letter to Parks &amp;amp; Recreation Dept requesting that pet waste station be added to Licton Springs park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communications task force: Joseph, Timothy, Tom Meyer, and Kathleen met May 8 and decided four points as recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that Licton Springs Community Council move its web outreach to the Love Licton blog managed by Tim and Amanda Crosley with the current Licton Springs Community Council website archived and still available via the blog.  Retain symbols for Licton Springs Community Council as cat-tail. Tim and Amanda will do a prototype that can be shown at June 20 meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to initiate a campaign to get out more knowledge throughout the neighborhood of Licton Springs Community Council&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make bulletin board in Licton Springs Park more prominent, perhaps move near restroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joseph is on sustainability committee for North Seattle College and will work with that group on community outreach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Licton Springs Community Council approved having a table at Debora Juarez's Live in D5 event June 30. Melanie and Kathleen can provide labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee Bruch presented information on a proposed Aurora Coalition and a draft of a letter to the City with information about safety concerns and steps for action had been circulated by email in draft form.  Lee is visiting different neighborhood groups to develop support for the coalition. Lee would like Licton Springs Community Council to join, to support the letter, and appoint a person to liaison with the coalition. After discussion, concern was raised that some missing Board members would want to vote on the request, so it is delayed until the June 20 meeting, but Thomas asked that an email discussion be generated among Board members. M/S/A meanwhile to authorize this statement for Lee with permission to use it: &lt;em&gt;The Licton Springs Community Council agrees with the conclusions raised by Lee Bruch on behalf of the Aurora Coalition and appreciates the proposed action steps in principle.  We will vote at our June 20, 2018 meeting on joining the coalition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visitors to the meeting then were invited to discuss some of their concerns and Lori Bienhoff discussed the lighting decision by Seattle Public Schools and the neighborhood meeting (which Melanie, Liz, Joseph also attended). The issue of access to the playfields at the Cascadia and RESMS schools was also discussed. Dissatisfaction was expressed that the School district would proceed with the lighting despite any opposition from the neighborhood. Lee Bruch offered materials from the (failed) attempt to get lighting controlled at Blanchet H.S. a few years earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melanie noted that Mary Amberg of the Seattle Police Dept agreed to attend the Licton Springs Community Council June 20 meeting and Kathleen will make sure it is advertised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amanda Crosley said she is very interested in helping with any community events and Kathleen will put her in touch with Jan Brucker who could not be here this evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was adjourned at 8:35 PM.  Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Council Meeting Minutes April 2018</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/council-meeting-minutes-april-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2018-04-15:/council-meeting-minutes-april-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL
Minutes of April 4 2018
Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133
Directors Present: Jan Brucker, Liz Kearns, Melanie Davies, Tom Meyer, and Kathleen Braden.
Jan convened the meeting at 6:30 PM. People attending introduced themselves.
Dave Kunkel, who has done so …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;LICTON SPRINGS COMMUNITY COUNCIL
Minutes of April 4 2018
Meridian Center for Health, 10521 Meridian Ave. N., Seattle 98133
Directors Present: Jan Brucker, Liz Kearns, Melanie Davies, Tom Meyer, and Kathleen Braden.
Jan convened the meeting at 6:30 PM. People attending introduced themselves.
Dave Kunkel, who has done so much to preserve Pillings Pond and its waterfowl, visited and
made a brief report on the property. He noted the section with the pond has been a designated
wetland and requires much upkeep. The property sold recently for $650,000. Dave has been
feeding and caring for over 100 fowl, mainly wood ducks (see photo), many of which he has
raised. Dave reviewed the history of the property since several people had come to the
meeting to show interest in it. He noted the family that purchased the property has an interest
in ducks, but most likely will be renting out the house. Dave is continuing to manage the
property. Jan reviewed past efforts, particularly by Dave Barber and neighborhood groups to
keep it preserved. The Parks Dept. does not seem inclined to take it on. There was a
suggestion to revive Friends of Pillings Pond as in the past, there had been non-profit status
for a group with that name. A neighbor who was attending out of interest in the property,
indicated she might like to help with that effort. Kathleen will send her contact information for
others who have been involved in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee Bruch made a presentation on Aurora Avenue and noted that it is a good
time to consider future improvements. Lee is hoping to create a coalition of
north end groups who have a stake in the corridor and has already approached
many neighborhood groups such as Haller Lake, Green lake, Bitter Lake,
Greenwood, ALUV. Part of the impetus came from a recent series of stories on KUOW radio
about the corridor. Lee has also been asked to write something for “The Urbanist”. The group
reviewed past efforts and asked Lee some questions about role of WSDOT, evolution of
thinking on the part of businesses along Aurora. A re-paving project will occur summer of
2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[secretary’s note: see list of District Five 2018 street and utility projects at D5 Projects 2018]
Spring event- Melanie noted ALUV liked the idea of a garage sale event, perhaps for school
parking lots. Jan also presented information on the Seattle Symphonic Band at North Seattle
College. A possibility of music in the park and budget was briefly discussed in an
introductory, exploratory way (no details).
The Council noted the March 26 meeting on Licton Village low barrier encampment and an
interest in the community on crime rates. There was also an analysis on crime rates nearby
done on NextDoor. [secretary note- Draft Minutes Community Advisory Meeting March 22
2018]
The minutes of March 21 2018 were presented and Joseph had several corrections, so he will
send them to Kathleen and the minutes can be approved. The Treasurer’s Report of March
2018 was approved.
Vote on Board Members: Per Articles VII and VIII of the Licton Springs Community Council
By-Laws, the following people, having been nominated at the March 2018 meeting, were voted
on and approved for terms through April 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joseph Amann&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ellen Beck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Brucker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Melanie Davies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liz Kearns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In accord with Article VII-4 on filling a vacancy, the Board elected as a member Tim Crosley
and his term will run through April of 2018 as well.
M/S/Unanimous approval to thank Tom Meyer who has served for many years. Tom
indicate he will still be available to assist with improving communication for the Council.
Officers- elected by the Board are as follows:
Thomas Stachiw – President
Joseph Amann- Vice-President
Kathleen Braden – Secretary
Ellen Beck-Treasurer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz Kearns gave an update on Licton Springs and Mineral Springs Parks, including how to
report campers in the parks to the City. The April 3 meeting with Randy Wiger of Parks Dept
on Mineral Springs Park had not been very well attended, possibly due to poor publicity.
There is a hope to get the disk golfing community more involved in future meetings.
Melanie Davies will contact Mary Amberg of Seattle Police Dept to see if she could attend a
June meeting on safety issues. Jan noted that we are lacking a representative to the Seattle
Police Advisory Committee and that Birgit Ardea might be interested in this service and Jan
will contact her about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was adjourned at 8:35 PM. Notes submitted by Kathleen Braden, Secretary&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Minutes"></category></entry><entry><title>Currents November 2016</title><link href="https://lictonsprings.org/currents-november-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Licton Springs Community Council</name></author><id>tag:lictonsprings.org,2016-11-01:/currents-november-2016.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-0.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Page 1" src="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-0.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Page 2" src="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Page 3" src="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-3.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Page 4" src="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-3.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-4.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Page 5" src="/images/currents/currents_nov_2016-4.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Currents"></category></entry></feed>